Nasr Kasrin (PhD)

■ n42r.me@gmail.com | 🗥 n42r.github.io | 🛅 nkasrin



Experienced technology leader with 15+ years in Al, data management solutions, and large-scale digital systems, spanning startups, global enterprises, and multi-million Euro R&D initiatives. In my PhD I invented The Basin Network, a next-generation data architecture for ML data interoperability and governance across divisions and enterprises.

I have led various teams, products, and initiatives bridging technical execution with strategic business alignment and enabling data-driven decisionmaking at scale.

Experience

Lead Solution Architect 2024 - present

PUMA SE, GLOBAL E-COMMERCE ENGINEERING

Herzogenaurach, Germany

- Led and scaled two cross-functional teams (4+4 engineers, +2 leads), driving a 20% performance boost for PUMA.com.
- Founded the Technical Cats of Ecomm, a platform for company-wide technical communication and alignment.
- Designed and developed an AI/LLM-powered framework, optimizing software engineering efficiency and automation.
- Resolved a critical, long-standing issue that was causing 90% order loss during high-traffic product launches.

Data Architecture Scientist | Doctoral Candidate | Founder-in-Exploration

2021 - 2024

Bamberg, Germany

- Invented The Basin Network: a data architecture for interoperability and integration of ML data across teams and enterprises. · Built MuzeAI: an open-source LLM-driven music recommendation prototype, with positive feedback from pilot users.
- Was co-founding a B2B startup (medical sector) for Al/LLM-driven solutions (left when joining PUMA).

Research Associate (Team Lead | Dev Lead | Architect | Data Solutions Engineer)

2015 - 2020

University of Bamberg (EU-Funded Manufacturing Project)

Bamberg, Germany

- Led a 4-year initiative to develop SIMUTOOL Data Management SaaS, which optimized operational efficiency by 30% for a €3.5M EU-funded aerospace manufacturing consortium.
- Engineered a read-heavy SaaS, ensuring seamless operations and future-proof scalable architecture.

R&D Engineer (AI) | Team Lead | Software Architect

2011 - 2014 Cairo, Egypt

- Led a team to build AI players for a commercial iOS mobile board game (Tawla), driving rankings from 3 to 4.5/5.
- Directed a team in building an iOS mobile app (Greetings Studio) increasing user engagement by 10x.
- Reduced feedback-development cycle times by 25% by coordinating cross-functional collaboration between technical and business.
- Saved the company 10-man months by investigating emerging trends and advising the CEO away from dead end directions.

Areas of Interest

Strategy Enterprise Data Strategy & Governance, Data Architecture & Data Mesh Implementation, Technical Communication Leadership Cross-functional collaboration, Product Management, Stakeholder Engagement & Data-Driven Decision Making **Tactical** Solution Architecture & Scalable Data Systems, AI & ML Data Interoperability

Domain Expertise AI, Metadata, Data (Integration | Governance | Interoperability | Cataloguing), Standardization, Domain Modeling

Data Engineering & AI/ML SQL, NOSQL, Python, data interoperability

Education

PhD. (Dr. rer. nat.): Data Architecture

OTTO-FRIEDRICH-UNIVERSITÄT BAMBERG, FACULTY OF INFORMATION SYSTEMS & APPLIED COMPUTER SCIENCE

Bamberg, Germany

MSc. (Masters of Science): Robotics / Artificial Intelligence

THE GERMAN UNIVERSITY IN CAIRO, FACULTY OF COMPUTER SCIENCE & ENGINEERING

BSc. (Bachelors of Science)

THE GERMAN UNIVERSITY IN CAIRO, FACULTY OF COMPUTER SCIENCE & ENGINEERING

Cairo, Egypt